you're a poet and uh this you were in a
group called flry right is that and you
replaced one of I guess one of the
founding members Natalie yeah Natalie M
and read a
lot that you weren't well received do
you know who I mean if they're turning
it back they're booing I mean I guess
the people that you trying to read The
Poetry too incorrect okay correct
me I will write about this extensively
um I was asked to join flry after
Natalie to I was told that Natalie left
apparently that was not the case okay
but that's what I was told okay and then
uh we prepared to go on tour and they
did not tell the fans that Natalie would
not be joining Marsha on the tour okay
so when I come on stage I do not
resemble Natalie in any shape way or
form right right um so immediately our
first show in Boston people are like
well who the is this but I
can sing and I know the songs so the
first show great time good job but now
the word is out Natalie ain't on the
tour right it's Amanda whoever this Brad
is it's Amanda seals well actually no I
had a name by then because I had done
MTV right so uh we now
went from Boston the next show that we
were doing
was somewhere else I can't remember but
maybe Philly okay
um and so I guess to just correct the
scenario it's not that people were mad
at me because of how I was delivering
the work it was that they felt
duped by the ticket sales because they
had bought tickets to see the flry they
knew and they were protesting that this
was not the flry they knew
nonetheless every time I won them over
because I am talented okay so every time
I won them over and uh I remember you
know being at Club Love in DC and they
had their backs turned to the stage and
it was like I had to it was like I was
on The Voice you know I had to get them
to turn them to spin them chairs around
but I sang My I sang my song that really
happened so they really my yes
what are you talking about yes do you
mind if I call you my you call me
whatever you like I mean I mean I mean
that's I'm talking about literally like
and then I'm over here all you gotta do
is say yes and they
like deny what you feel let me undress
you baby maybe this maybe this little
skinny light skinn got something
with her yeah that really happened but I
wasn't doing poetry I was singing okay
so okay you with all like okay they like
this they like aanda okay yeah but
Marsha
never made it any
easier
why why yes why why did okay natal I
think I think I think I think this is
now see what I'm saying I think I don't
know okay this your point of view this
your POV I think that they wanted me to
quit why because then she could proceed
on the tour by herself and she was in
the process of going into her solo
career and the way that I was treated
was so just shitty that I think they
were really trying to force me to quit
and they almost did they almost got me
out of that and you said honestly it
wasn't even me who said it it was our
drummer at the time Daryl and me and
Daryl didn't even rock with each other
but he spoke into me and he was like cuz
I was really like the people out of here
out of
here because every show we would come on
the stage and she would not even say my
name
and every night she would say to me okay
so this is how we're going to start the
show tonight so I never got a rhythm can
you imagine you on the football field
and every night the quarterback coming
with a play you ain't never ran before
you ain't never seen this he like
all right we want to do we're going to
do a 52 banana split with a cherry on
top you like we ain't never done
that before I thought we was doing the
Banana parfait right so that's what
every single night and it would get more
and more egregious I just never forget
we was in North Carolina and she was
like all right so how we're going to do
this is I'm going to come on stage I'm
going to start singing um butterflies
and then you're going to come on stage
but you're going to like dap up the the
The Other M the musicians what but I'm
already going to be singing I'm already
going to be singing you're going to DAP
up the musicians and you're going to
come on stage after you dap up the
musican you'll just like start singing
and then we'll just do the show and I
was like so at no point you're going to
say like this is Amanda seals and she
was like I just don't want to I just
don't want to disrupt the audience now
if I'm being generous maybe she was just
trying to mitigate the
I don't know maybe she was just trying
to mitigate the the nastiness from the
audience but like if that was the case
she wasn't communicating that to me so I
felt very very very very isolated in the
situation and like nobody was
communicating this to me so at no point
in time after Natalie and after group
okay you do the first show in Boston and
then you go to Philly or you go to
Baltimore wherever did she say Natalie
is no longer in the group we have a
lovely other lady named Amanda and she's
unbelievable
no no and we didn't do press and I
remember Wendy Williams so we get to
Atlanta okay
now um what people didn't know was that
even before any of this had started I
was music director so oh God come on you
months before you ain't supposed to do
that I didn't even know he was the music
director I was already this before
but then once you find out you like I
can't do this well no my point is that I
had an Insider oh oh okay okay okay okay
so you have you have some good int okay
that's all I'm saying yes so you know so
he going to tell you
everything all you gotta do is say
yes what you feel let me undress you
baby so he's telling you so we're in
Atlanta and I had a solo song that I
would sing that was one of my songs so
we're in Atlanta and um after rehearsal
he pulls my coat he's like hey um she
trying to she trying to cut your song
but she didn't tell me this he's like
she literally cut your song from the set
list yeah which would mean that we would
be in the middle of the show and I would
realize that my song is not
happening and you going to be out there
like damn what my
song so uhoh I said I said for sure for
sure for sure okay but now we got to get
in the car together me and Mara we got
to get in the car together to go back to
the hotel o
on the way to the car my boy Dwight
willacy texts me and says hey you listen
to Wendy Williams also like why am I
just casually listening to William
Williams but he's like turn on Wendy
Williams natti is on Wendy
Williams natti is on Wendy Williams
talking about the real flow tree I don't
know who VI Amanda is I'm not sure how
she got involved but I am the real flow
tree I am the real flow tree I'm working
on my accent I'm the real flow tree and
so if you're going to these shows just
know you're not supporting the real flow
tree we're s sitting in the
car and I just found out you trying to
cut my song and I said did you try to
cut my song from the show I don't know
what you're talking about I said I was
told that you're trying to cut my song
for the show she's like who told you
that she actually didn't ask she
actually didn't ask um to my
recollection she didn't ask but
nonetheless it was just like I want my
song in the
show and so she's like all right
whatever but now I'm text I'm seeing
from Dwight that like Natalie is on
Wendy Williams talking crazy so I up to
the room and so now I'm like yo
apparently Nat's on Wendy Williams so
now we turn this on the car we
sitting in the car listen to this she
ain't saying nothing we get to the hotel
I go to the room I'm still listening
Natalie is burning me up she's like I'm
on the see it's not real she's fake this
is all fake fake fake
fake so now Marsha calls me like did you
listen I said yeah what you GNA do about
it nothing
I said oh okay and this is this is a
trend of me not being protected
okay okay did you actually think she was
going to protect you considering that
she had never given you the proper
recognition the proper identification
she never given you the prop I shouldn't
have but I did okay I shouldn't have but
I did because I always expect and this
is also a flaw but I always hope for the
best in people because Shannon
you hoping people what you have what you
do
yourself we talked about this earlier we
got to stop that I know but it feels so
defeated to do it but it's it's true but
it feels like you're giving
into the T it just feels like you're
giving into the worst parts of existence
to do it that's what it feels like it
feels
very um nealis to just really give in
but it is the only way that you can
really protect self mhm and my my
co-host Supreme on my radio show always
he' be like
Amanda most people are full of if
you would just accept this you would
have such less heartache and I'm like I
know but so I just want them to not be
so now okay so now she didn't do nothing
your work she didn't do anything you
feeling some type of way too now I can
see it I see it right now well um what
most people think is feeling some type
of way for me is actually just me being
hurt it's really it's just it just reads
because of the type of human I am and
the way that my my my self is set up it
reads as anger but it really is deep
hurt that's what you're reading and
I am
betrayal and I'm giving so much of
myself to this and to your point ain't
been right up to this point so it
is a straw on a camel ah you know MH M
so I'm like
okay I'm out now I I call the the music
director like yo this just got
ridiculous he's like yo I'm about to
come to your room let's talk I'm like
okay this never comes to the room
I come downstairs he's talking to a
white chick at the bar I'm like God the
one that you used to I thought he came
up there just for one last SW r that
what I was break it cuz that would have
made sense yeah for sure the pain away
you know but no so I then call my home
girl to take me to the airport okay so I
call my mom and I'm like book me a
ticket I'm out of here I'm out of here
because I've reached my wits end and
again I have no allies here I I had I
had a manager who was none of the above
okay this sent me on the road with
no
contract talking about well you should
just be happy they asked you what so I
want you to follow the themes in this
interview I want you to follow two
themes misunder stood and not protected
I want you to follow those themes okay
because you've notied it's themes you
follow the theme of racism but I want
you to follow those other themes because
they're important they're important to
understanding someone like me and when
you have not been protected and you are
misunderstood what are you going to
naturally develop defense mechanism for
sure you because you have to protect
yourself yes there's no other way no
they will tear you up they will eat you
alive right and if you're if you're
creating these things things also within
the context of autism within the context
of already speaking a certain way
thinking a certain way you are setting
yourself up for a very hard road but
you're not even the one setting yourself
up I take that back you are set up for a
hard Road in the midst of all of this
though you are brilliant you have talent
and you are in a field that that's the
only way that those things really work
in you know it's not like I can go be
the theatric seals like at the
hospital you feel me like this is where
I have to be so so I was about to leave
I was about to leave and um the drummer
who we used to we used to clash cuz we
both had these like really big
personalities that we hadn't matured
into yet you know um he hit me and he
said you can't leave you cannot leave
because if you leave they'll
win and want you to leave and you cannot
let them win and he said because later
in life you will look back on this and
you will say I I stayed and I was strong
and it's going to
matter it's going to matter and he was
right and so that
night um I ended up saying I came back
and we had a show that
night and we had a conversation before
the show and you know the 48 Laws of
Power it can be used in a very
duplicitous fashion but sometimes it is
useful when you're dealing with
folks that just can't see you because of
their own blind spots and I'm a very
very emotionally intelligent person and
so a lot of times I end up having to do
the emotional labor for other people to
get us through right it's
exhausting it's exhausting can I ask you
this in your
life how many people do you feel
that have protected you and understood
you like you want a number yeah because
you say it on one hand now I mean at
this point I've I've I've amassed an
incredible amount and it's been a
beautiful Evolution okay um but up until
my youth
yeah in my youth I mean my mom that was
your
rock and
you know it's like it's just there's
different processes right like I will
say like my gymnastics coach you speak
very high you know what you speak very
highly of your gymnastics coach and
there are a couple of teachers at John
Phillips High School Dr Phillips Dr
Phillips high school that you speak in
glowing terms about and then when you
speak of them you
radiate you don't speak you don't
radiate When you mention anybody else's
name but when you mention those people's
names your mother your gymnastics coach
the people at the uh the instructors at
Dr Phillips High School you
radiate what was it about them that
caused them to not only understand
Amanda but was willing to protect
Amanda your mom I get that's your mom
she's supposed to because they because
they they they saw what some people
consider as flaws they saw his
strengths you know I remember when I
started going to therapy I started going
to therapy cuz I was like you know
people keep telling me that no one likes
me and I do not understand did you
believe it that no one likes me yeah
yeah because I had low self-esteem okay
so I'm just like I don't I don't but I
don't
understand and she I remember her asking
me well what are the reasons why people
say they don't like
you and I told her I said my
tone um I'm they feel that I'm uh like
too detail oriented like it's
annoying um you know they tell me like
like they like me being detail oriented
they take it as nitpicky
right um that I am too demanding whereas
like for me it's like well no it's like
it's more so just me holding you
accountable um they say that I
am mean but in my version of it it's
like well no I'm just being honest and
so we started working on me being better
at understanding like the neurotypical
like the normal way that things are read
so that I could better protect myself
like that may be the truth but you don't
got to tell it right
now you know it and good for you right
hold that right hold that you don't got
to tell it right now
um it may have been a yes or no question
but people need extra words
I lost a job because I was answering yes
or no questions how you lose a job if
you answer yes or no cuz you added
because he they were emailing me yeah
asking me yes or no questions and my
responses were yes yes and no and then
finally I got an email that said you
know what we decided to go with somebody
else because by your by your responses
it seems like you're not
interested well you say answer yes or no
so now you understand me it took us a
little bit but you here so I'm so they
want you to say yes I would love to have
the job because I think this is amazing
opportunity for me and I just love this
company I thank
you but get out there and dance
but Amanda and black people do it to
each other Amanda we had the
conversation up earlier what did we say
if you
understand the rules no I didn't
understand the rules I'm just talking
then I didn't understand the rules I
didn't understand the rules to learn so
I was saying that the therapy helped you
yes but even still it's like
understanding the rules and like you
know then you are who you are like that
ends up being in conflict with each
other so often you know what I'm saying
like you understand the rules but you're
like in order for me to to like play
this game I got to like do a whole
renovation of self that's not going to
be an upgrade it's just me really just
trying to mask to become um palatable to
you but don't you think realistically
there are a lot more people that dress
in Halloween costumes year round as
opposed to just on that day I do not
want to be those people and those are
not the people that changed the world
and that's what I'm here to do and I
literally went and got my masters
because rich boova on the campus of
purchas college stopped me and held my
hand because he was a psychic and he
would always do readings for people and
he just held my hand and was like well
you got to go get your Masters and I was
like God
I thought I was done with this and he
was like no you got to go get your
Masters because you're going to change
the world and you're going to need it to
do it you believe in psychics I believe
in a lot oh my goodness how can you not
believe in psychics and believe in God
no no no what do you wait let's take
listen take a moment let's take a moment
let's take a moment
yes if you believe in God then you
believe in a spiritual power that is
greater than all of us you also believe
that there are people who are able to
access that in ways that others cannot
do you not that's what our pastors do
that's what people who are Catholics
belief priests are doing and for all
intents and purposes when we pray we are
attempting to contact that power we are
attempting to just let me finish we are
attempting to tap in to that power to
tap into that energy and bring it to us
as we are continuing to bring it to them
now when we vilify the idea of psychic
or witches Etc a lot of times what's
mixed into that is that ain't got
nothing to do with actual connection to
Spirit okay there are people who are
operating in dark spaces and dark places
but there are people who are tapped in
that just have different names and so
the idea of a psychic like I'm not
calling him a psychic a medium a medium
or somebody who is literally just more
connected I am very connected to like
I'm empathic I can feel I'm very
connected to just nature to the the the
vibration of things because I want to be
but also because I'm an artist right
like I can make something from nothing
like there's something that is really
unique in that ability to do so so when
I'm talking about someone who is able to
read you it's not like there are it's
not that they're dealing with dark magic
it's that they are able to see their
profits so it's just language but as
long as it's done in love it's all
coming from the same
place fastor seem to have been accessing
people's bank accounts a lot lately that
is very true and that is why we have to
always be careful about who is at the
pum pit so you're me one of your first
jobs in New York was a radio host how'd
you get you you know what I feel like I
didn't finish that previous story go
ahead tell it fre tell it oh flry yes
let me finish it okay tell it cuz I
thought you was done with a because well
no well I just feel like it's important
to note that with the 48 Laws of Power I
realized in that moment
oh I have to win the I have to let her
win the battle to win the war okay and
my ego has to be removed in order to do
that and I that's something I had to
learn in that moment like ego is not
serving you here and I really don't have
an ego in that way like I can really
often see like there's a bigger picture
here and so I had to let her know that I
was not a threat to her and I realized
that for some reason she was like saying
treating me that way right I don't know
if that was her so you actually had a
conversation with her right before show
and I had to tell her like I just want
you to like me I just want you to feel
safe with me here I just want you to see
me as someone who is not trying to step
on your toes cuz that's what it feels
like and if that's not what it is so be
it but if that's what it is I just want
you to know that that's not what I'm
trying to do so I had to make myself
small so that she could not feel like I
was trying to take her place and after
that we had no problems I don't know
that Amanda You Don't Know Much Amanda
yet I mean I'm I'm the man have made
herself shrink down I mean it went down
to Honey I Shrunk the kid baby I know
what to
do that's the part that people don't
understand is that I it's not even that
you necessarily are
shrinking it's that you understand it's
like if you're on a field and you know
that in this Play I'm Not the star yes
in this play all I need to do is block
this so that this ball can get to this
point yes that's the point and I am that
person I know what role I'm playing on
the fields yes you can be good at any
game if you understand the rules there
you go from an hour ago and don't talk
to me like that dab it up no can I call
you my sister time
out can I call you my sister dab it up
no come on you you I I want I you agree
with me because what you're saying is
not accurate to the situation yes it is
is no because the game we're talking
about two different games no in that
moment you realize you I'm not arguing
that point I'm not arguing that point
you were saying that it's easier if you
understand the game and all I was saying
was that I don't know that it's easier
but it definitely is important cuz it
wasn't necessarily easy let me tell you
but it was necessary and I didn't and if
I'm if I'm being honest I don't know
that I would call it the game as much as
I would call I mean I use that as a
metaphor but it's like you could use
that example in a in an operating room
like if you're the nurse you not with
the scalpel but you are important and
you know your role in this situation and
that is fine it's the lieutenant and the
and the captain right like you just have
to understand that and when you do your
ego doesn't matter because you your ego
is not based on being at the top your
ego is based on not your ego is based on
being useful yes and that that really is
what I feel like a lot of people in this
Society are not realizing we have this
main character energy that a lot of
people are just really built into and
it's like everybody needs to feel like
they're the star they're at the top
their name is on the ETC and there's so
many other ways to be of value and a lot
of people are not cut for being the
leader they not cut for being the star
and they in these positions and they
don't know how to act and
they're actually really being you stay
on the tour you work at UH you and uh
Mara Mara y'all hash out your diff you
hash them out or you just y'all make
peace to get through the
tour no after that it was fine because I
had I let her know that I wasn't a
threat to her so then it's not a problem
how would you it was her it was her show
right so
how child I can't you know all all I can
do is my
best so you did end up leaving the show
no I did the whole tour you did the
whole tour did the whole whole tour and
then after we were going to be a group
called Flor tree remix and so
um her manager kept playing around with
my manager around it and then she had me
make a MySpace page for us and then she
didn't accept the friend request
oh yep and that was the end of it and
then I just did my own music and I put
out my album life
experience have you talked to her
since I I actually saw her at Usher Show
recently and she went to hug me and I
was like no I'm good come on you didn't
do that come come on now don't be don't
be don't be Petty Le Bell how was that
petty cuz she she really after all them
years yeah after all them years what
what am I hugging her for that's not my
peoples I don't first of all I'm not a
hugger in general but that's not yeah
see I'm not Petty I'm not phony I'm not
going to hug people that are not my
people if you treat me like in real
life don't try to hug me at a part cuz I
won't hug you back it's a song If you
treat me like in life don't try to
hug me at a
party cuz I won't hug you back that's
not song you made it but here's the
thing I can't believe you I can't
believe you would do that that was that
was I am who I am people know who I am
and that's a beautiful thing the person
I am is beautiful because you don't
never have to guess people like me are a
blessing you don't ever have to guess
and so much of this life is people not
wanting to deal with the real and just
hiding in the shadows and instead of
honoring honor is a strong word but
instead of you know regarding and
respecting people who are straight ahead
we treat them like they are a nuisance
we treat them like they are um A
disruption when really they are a gift
because it really removes the guesswork
of subtext it removes the guesswork of
um ulterior motives I am what I am what
you see is what you get what whatever
you hear me saying is what I'm saying it
and and to me that is such an easier
route you know and and I found people in
my life over time that really see that
that is such a a dope way to exist and
it's been a blessing so when you asked
me earlier about like people who have
protected me and like people who
understand me like it's those people
people who see that as a gift not as an
attack have you ever hugged anybody that
you didn't like or Shake shook their
hands I mean I'm sure I did when I was
less um sure of myself and when I felt
like I needed to play the game you know
I've had an I had you know I've had
self-esteem and inferior to complex
issues for a long time and I've had to
learn how to love myself as who I am and
be okay with that and also understand
the repercussions of
that
okay it's okay we can move on now we we
good with we good with Mara oh yeah I
want to talk about the radio I want to
talk about you because you at the intro
you've done a lot of things yes your
your resume is
extensive no seriously no no no no no
bull job no real talk M
and I don't know if you really know or
maybe people haven't told you maybe you
just and we we all wired like this we
kind of hear more hear the negativity
than the positive because being the next
Prof athletes the losses haunt me more
than the wins right I remember a loss
way more than I doesn't that suck it's
like so irritating that our brains are
wired that way it's like how this is not
helpful yeah yeah the parades don't
bring me the
joy that the hurt and the
losses I feel you want to join Club sh
Shay become an official member by
hitting that subscribe button where you
never know who's going to be joining us
for drinks and conversation don't be
late to the party because you know we
like to do something before two
something